Fuji hunt John Flacco speaking hello
John how are you it's Frank hi Frank how
Frank how are we okay I guess you're all
set and ready to go yeah I guess so okay
that's great I just got back in from
lunch and I'm glad everything worked out
time wise with us yeah
you're on the Hall of talk show and
listeners will be tuning in to hear all
the news about the new Fuji materials so
it might be a good idea for us to start
off with maybe a timeline as far as
Fuji's development of these is Maybe
explain why Fuji even decided to get
involved with holographic materials in
the first place
reseller photographic films and all
kinds of things like that and they found
that uh there was one uh
cuts out there for films that has not
really been serviced very much in the
past it's it's been serviced up and down
different companies got in and out of it
Supply is
at times quality goes up and
up and down
have the capability of of coding high
quality films they thought that's a
market they could get into also there's
some thought about the future in data
storage where you can store information
on various different kinds of
substrates and holography is one of the
things
you know looking at it as possibly a
full kind of Technology Yeah so
basically with the holographic data
storage
the film based based holography part of
this is actually just Fuji getting your
feet wet really it could you could look
at it that way it's a possibility yeah
and when did Fuji start has this been in
development for a long time
I don't think it's been a long time it
might have been about
uh
a year
okay
about a year ago and then they started
doing some market research
probably
a year ago last
yeah
the last five minutes
I guess the summer fall of 2004 it
started to do some market research on it
that's a pretty quick turnaround time
conception to actually bringing it to
the market yeah I think it
you know I can't say before that what
they were doing or thinking
as far as I know that's
the whole thing worked through and again
we have to remember there
there so they can
do a lot of testing pretty quickly
so let's move on to now that we know
that the product has been developed and
it's out there I'm assuming it's out
there I'm not sure is it's available for
order yet or not quite there yeah
just announced it via press release
pan
one from one from U.S itself
our plan is to have a film available by
the end of January
and uh
the available
in 30 by 40 sheets
see by 60
one meter by 10mm
and from what I understand from our
lunch last week at
time at least Fuji doesn't plan on
supplying any other formats other than
those that you just mentioned right
we aren't because of the simple fact
that we're
haven't
had the film out there we you know we've
done market research and study we've
trial on the test
we thought it'd be best to bring it in
into what we feel is the commercial
Market which uses the largest volumes of
film and thus once some value
established then we
sizes like your listeners but
despite only two and a half by two and a
half or four by five and there's always
the option at this point in time for uh
someone to order a few 30 by 40
centimeter sheets and just cut them down
yeah basically that that's the way to
get around it
quantity we'll have would be 10
I mean a couple people
buy some like that or
who will you know they can just buy one
box and it'll probably last them for the
year now since since this film was
panchromatic is it do you recommend any
specific safe light or no safe flight at
all with it no you can use a safe light
as a matter of fact it's um
down at the lowest rate at about five
seven five seventy nanometers
so we've actually used a very dark Amber
type filter as
okay but we've also found
that there's a Amber
uh
LED type light it's a company called
Opti opt LED I think it's called and
they
sell an amber
ID that's been used very successfully as
a safe flight
by covering half of it with a green
filter it is very very bright
yeah clearly oh that's great yeah
but we're happy about that or you know
you could you have to experiment of
course
the lights could be used
by quite a bit yeah
yeah now we spoke a little bit last week
about comparisons just for general
purposes to agfa and you gave some
information as far as
an increase in resolution over AG fifth
my notes are correct but yet the speed
is very consistent or maybe one stop
around a half a stop slower than the egg
movement of the material okay um
resolution is around even lines per
millimeter of meter of greater than
three
the grain size is about 30 to 40
nanometers okay
it's not the fine
but it's very fine
oh I did see some reflection Holograms
created with it and they were very
impressive yeah some of the things that
people told about them
are very little noise
get a lot of really
yeah you know good that of course
contrast yeah yeah
[Music]
that's really good
like I said the brightness is
do a transfer
as far as processing the film pretty
much any type of processing chemistry
that happens to be a holographer's
favorite I understand well uh yes
basically pretty much work it uses you
know the normal process that you would
use for holography you know
uh different people have their own
little
little chemical mixes that they
said this
Webster's more
Pyro
mixes out there pyro was actually always
my favorite yeah I mean it's a
you know from the black and white film
low contrast fine
very long tonal range and
the life itself very nicely too
yeah
do you happen to know offhand any of the
specific formulas that were being used
for the testers that they were using
um
that was out of the ordinary that was uh
in the marketplace yeah I mean I can say
that um you know as
the real whole name of bougie
hunt photographic chemicals Incorporated
so and we're a wholly owned subsidiary
of photo film limited Japan
most of our products that we deal with
are photographic chemicals like
like local Mini Labs or mass retailers
so
so our Forte has actually chemicals
in a lot of respects so we will be in
future once we uh you know the the
holographic film gets out there into the
marketplace we will most definitely be
looking
uh total processing systems
includes a developer that's optimized
for
the film
you basically just have water and
and then we want to
produce or provide a state
because one of the issues that you have
with holography is
it's not really like a black and white
film where it's fixed and washed
normally
[Music]
then how do you stabilize the image
image and doubt over to it yeah so we're
looking at
in that vein
are
we can primarily of manually developing
film or are you planning on developing
some sort of a automation system we're
looking at possibly do
automation
down the line after
as far as Machinery okay
okay
there's an awful lot of old photo type
setting systems out there that um
the laser image centers like the
linotronics and
the different fact I think act for one
time is called copy graphic you know
before purchase copy graphic
I used to have these little desktop
processing units that uh were about the
size of a laser printer that you'd feed
your cassettes through and it would
develop your film
or your paper type of media that would
come out of the laser photo type Setters
oh yeah
would converting a
equipment like that be that far out of
the question using uh developer and
bleach I don't think so I mean
uh
it be done uh probably the the thing
that you'd have to watch is what exact
chemicals you use because obviously
there are
the plumbing and what everything is made
out of has a lot to do with whether you
can
you cast us
so that that would be one of the things
probably be the
easiest way we would like to see
forward into an actual system because
a lot of the bigger machines that do
very large
processes
are kind of not being used anymore yeah
yeah so they might be available for a
song let's say yeah on eBay or whatnot
yeah exactly and then just take them
clean them out
and if you decide that you want to go
with a route of d19 and some fixer yeah
just feed your 30 by 40 centimeter sheet
you just have to figure out the timing
that it needs to go through the rollers
really that's that's typically all you
would have to do yeah it's not really
really that hard yeah so isn't that
something yeah I mean it is possible and
there's some people that have looked at
it but haven't done a a lot of work in
it but I think I think then the next the
coming year
we're going to be talking to
uh producing hologographers
various display work and trying to get a
system down that can work automated yeah
yeah
you don't have any pricing together on
any of the materials yet do you uh not
specifically because we're again it's
even though we said we were working on
this for about a year it's all coming to
do it now
I was looking at
proposals and things like that and I
mean for your listeners
you know four by five sheets they would
probably be running in the
approximately
as close as I can come to as an estimate
for film
no no plans on plates right
plates are are kind of uh a whole other
thing for us in that of course
um the film is manufactured in
and uh
facility obviously is there to make lots
of rolls of film
or lots of sheets of film what have you
so their their expertise in coding is on
a thinner
flexible type of substrate
when you get into thicker plate
substrates they do obviously have the
technology because they coat some of the
Coatings for
but
the difficulty is of course those are
the cost of those are are quite High
shipping from Japan of
somewhat problematic because
things like that so
it's not out of the question
I think we're going to have to see how
forms in the marketplace and what kind
of Demands we can get out of it
plates become
an issue
moving forward we will definitely
consider
it's not that inexpensive anymore to
have things manufactured in Japan this
is no no it's like everything else yeah
the costs are going up and resources are
well everything's kind of
kind of China yeah
I know 20 years ago a lot of the bicycle
manufacturers they started to have their
frames manufactured in Japan so if you
bought a Raleigh or if you bought a
Schwinn they were British and American
companies but the actual frames the
production facilities had shifted to
Japan
and then of course you had your Japanese
makers like Fuji and whatnot making
bicycles
that's so expensive to manufacture the
frames in Japan that even the Japanese
bicycle companies now have their frames
manufactured in Taiwan yeah so if you
buy a Fuji bicycle now even though it's
Japanese company that frames
manufactured in Taiwan
yeah
it's the same thing anymore anywhere
what is the thickness of the substrate
uh the total thickness of the film is
about 8 .9 mil okay the Emulsion itself
is about
okay
yeah I don't for lack of memory right
here I can't remember how that compares
to uh perhaps the slavage film or the
old agfa film as far as thickness I know
agfa had a pretty nice thickness to it
to work with
back code on the film
film curl okay
let me ask you this is triacetate that's
not an anti-halation back no it's not
all right no we found some people it's
one of those things you can't have it on
there if you're gonna try to have the
film
usable for for Masters and transfers
yeah exactly yeah
yeah all right well you I did receive
the first press release
do you have any other materials that you
could send to me that I could place on
the website for when people listen to
the interview
um I have the the latest press release
that we uh if you know what the date on
your professional is I'd have to pop it
open on the screen hold on
let's see
I hope everything doesn't shut down on
me we'll lose 20 minutes of a show here
oh December 28 2005. okay how about if I
put that up on the website that's good
um I have uh provisional technical
technical documentation
that could be uh probably put there it
really just provides what uh
lasers can
be response curves
yeah
I have contacted a few people as far as
their willingness to
take this material and do a couple shots
and give feedback on it so if you'd like
I can get that information to you yeah
that would be great
and
dare we say that if possibly maybe five
the first five people that would want to
contact you to get a sample to work with
so yes okay I would say that we could
easily do that at the first five people
that contact me via email and uh
J
at
f
u j i h u n t
usa.com and we'll send them
send them 4x5 to try out okay and I'll
also have that email address right on
the website now keep in mind folks this
is the first five people not the first
55.
and of course this is a global show so
you know when this goes up online
whatever time it goes up
it's going to go up I mean it's going to
if I put this up at eight o'clock at
night
that's going to make it as an advantage
for some people but for some other
person around the world where it might
be three o'clock in the morning and
they're sleeping they're going to be out
of luck
so much having three kids and trying to
be fair with three kids all the time has
led me to believe that you know what
it'll go up when it goes up and the
first five people in contact gets the
stuff right you know what I mean because
I can read the emails now that's not
fair
it was three o'clock in the morning here
that's I'm sorry that's the best I can
do yeah
well I want to thank you guys for lunch
it was delicious it was actually over in
in that area today my wife and I went
over to a uh a Bavarian restaurant
that's over there to get some some
Dolly deli food yeah so uh right over
there oh it's an absolutely gorgeous day
it's it's it's unbelievable I think
we're gonna pay for this yeah
pay for this weather is there anything
that you'd like to add to this interview
that we have not um
that we've not talked about I think that
pretty much covers it that I could think
of I mean we're really excited about
bringing this film to market we've had
some
famous people uh in the holographic
Community tested do you want to give any
information about those famous people uh
well we had Anna Maria Nicholson look at
the film we had Auggie moved look at the
film
um
Perry John Perry at Hollow North
uh
John Taylor right uh Rob Taylor yes yeah
oh what was the other sorry about that
Rob triple take triple take oh no
kidding yeah in California
Dinesh enjoy yeah yeah we've gotten
really excellent feedback from everyone
they really like the film
and good
to work with
comes
it's going to size that they're
looking at what's nice is I'm knew that
agfa material is basically
not some out there still but very little
and for those
pulse if they needed a film to keep on
making images and
we'll help them do that so
lastly
if someone is out there we'll say it's
uh either John Smith or Sally Smith
and they're already using materials and
they've been using them for a while why
would they want to switch you what is
the incentive for them to switch over to
hagfa if they already have the protocol
in place with the other materials well I
think it you the opportunity to
have a secondary supplier if issues
arise
it also gives you the opportunity to
possibly use some of the newer low-cost
lasers that are out there if you're
using an older system
you want it to upgrade but
but you know you were limited to the 10
that are using this
this is the opportunity
to upgrade to a different kind of
possibly a cheap more powerful laser
dramatic film
wide range
to choose from and of course Fuji is a I
would say the largest manufacturer
of films in the world and
you know we can't make it
[Music]
our quality speaks
a quality product
that
do emotion
the great shelf life and
image
has just the fact
that low noise
yeah it's very nice stuff to look at
from what we could see under the
conditions
that we were in yes exactly I mean
that's that speaks volumes for it right
it really does yeah so we're going to
actually introduce it uh the film at the
photonics West show
[Music]
San Jose
hope
to uh
so go to the International
play holography
in Wales yeah we'll also actually we're
hoping to have
uh
the work some work
on marketing so
um Orlando in
oh that's nice too yeah so I mean we're
serious that we know that the market has
been
let's say under service
we believe there is quite a potential
out
for holography in not only the Hobby
World but
for displays
I think our film
you know if
ever interested in putting a
exhibit together using
materials for people come to that would
be a good
probably would think about that once we
get it rolling out in the market people
are actually using it and making more
and more Holograms then we could
sponsored show or an orchestra
so many artists out there right now it's
hard to say whose work we would uh
we would like to
suppose yeah any
one and when will you see Greg next he's
not sitting in the room with you right
there no no he'll be here next week
sent me a date tell him that if you if
you can and you see him tell him that
the date's okay okay all right I think
February sometime I think uh eighth or
something
and then I'll get back to him on that
he's not in touch with email or anything
right now how is he okay all right I'll
do that
all right and then this show will
probably go up later tonight and I'll
get the email I don't know if you're on
the email list or not I'm not sure okay
yeah it's the email list that goes out
to everyone announcing that there's a
new show so that announcement will go
out either later tonight or early
tomorrow morning depending on how much I
get finished I think I'm just going to
use the show as is I don't even think
anything needs to be edited on this it's
not too much I don't think no just as is
put it up and we're ready to go and
everybody can listen to it yeah okay
sounds great all right John thank you
very much for being on the show thank
you and Greg for lunch had a great time
and uh
a lot of luck and success with your new
holographic material and welcome to the
club thank you very much all right talk
to you later you have a good day bye
bye-bye